The problem we're trying to solve here is to count the number of
这次我们要解决的问题
times we need to roll five dice to get a Yahtzee.
是计算我们要掷五个骰子多少次 才能得到一只快艇
Five dice might seem a little bit too complicated,
五个骰子似乎有点复杂
so a good idea is to start simple.
一开始我们还是简单点好
Let's assume we're only rolling two dice for now.
所以我们暂时先只掷两个骰子
And the goal is to count and return the number
目标是不断计算并返回出投掷次数
of rolls we need until we get those two dice to match.
直到两个骰子点数相同为止
Once we figure out the code for that,
一旦我们写出了这个操作的代码
we can then modify it and add more dice to it and solve the actual problem.
我们就可以修改一下 往里面添加更多骰子 从而解决真正的问题
When writing code for a complicated problem,
要写代码来解决复杂的问题
it's always a good idea to break it down that way.
有个常用的好办法 就是像这样把问题拆分开来
Think of an abstract or simple version of the problem.
把问题抽象化或简化
Write the code you need to solve that,
写出解决简化版问题的代码
and then build on that code till you solve the actual problem you have.
然后在那个代码的基础上进行修改 直到能解决真正的问题为止
To count the number of rolls needed for two dice to match,
要计算让两个骰子点数相同的投掷次数
we will be declaring this function called keepRolling.
我们需要声明这个叫 keepRolling (继续掷) 的函数
It doesn't take any input arguments,
该函数没有任何输入参数
and it returns an integer value which is the number of rolls needed.
而且会返回一个整数值 也就是需要投掷的次数
To simulate the dice rolling,
要模拟掷骰子的情景
we'll be using the function rollDice that we've created in the previous lesson.
我们需要用上节课创建好的 rollDice (掷骰子) 函数
rolleDice returns a random number
rollDice 会返回一个随机数
between 1 and 6 which basically simulates rolling a dice.
范围在 1 到 6 之间 模拟了掷一颗骰子的情景
Here we're calling it twice,
因此我们需要调用这个函数两次
and setting them into the variables dice1 and dice2.
并将它们的值分别赋给变量 dice1 (骰子 1 ) 和 dice2 (骰子 2)
Then I'll declare another integer variable
然后在这再声明一个整数变量
here that we'll keep track of the number of rolls.
以便我们跟踪投掷次数
I'll initialized it to 1 because so far,
我把这个变量初始化为 1 因为到目前为止
we've rolled those two dice once.
我们只掷了一次那两个骰子
Next, we need to keep re-rolling our dice every time they don't match.
接下来 只要骰子点数不同 我们就需要不断重掷
We could use a while loop that checks if the dice don't match,
我们可以用 while 循环来检查骰子点数是否相同
and then re-roll the dice inside.
然后在循环里进行重掷
That is while dice1 and dice2 are not equal,
也就是当 dice1 和 dice2 不相等时
then we want to retry rolling our dice and hope for a match.
我们就要重掷骰子以期获得相同的点数
So inside our while loop,
所以在 while 循环里
we'll just call this rollDice function again for dice1 and dice2,
我们再次调用这个 rollDice 函数来给 dice1 和 dice2 赋值
and add 1 to count this extra roll that we did.
然后给 count 加 1 把这次投掷加进投掷次数中
Remember that we only add 1 here because
记住 这里我们只需加 1
those two calls simulate rolling those two dice just once.
因为这两个调用函数模仿的是同时掷两个骰子的情景
Eventually at some point,
最后总会有那么一次
those two rolls would return the same value,
两个骰子返回出了相同的值
and dice1 would match dice2,
于是 dice1 等于 dice2
and this while loop would end.
while 循环得以结束
At that point, we could safely return the number
这个时候 我们就可以安全地
of counts that we've counted so far which
把迄今为止得到的计值返回出来
would indicate the number of rolls we needed to get that match. That looks pretty good.
该值即得到相同点数所需的投掷次数 看起来不错
Let's trace that code with some examples and see if it works.
现在我们让代码来执行一些例子 跟踪看看能不能奏效
So the first thing that happens here is we call
首先
this rollDice function and save its return value in dice1.
我们调用这个 rollDice 函数 将其返回值赋给 dice1
Let's say that randomly returned the number 4.
假设随机返回出的值为 4
The next line calls rollDice again for dice2.
下一行再次调用 rollDice 赋值给 dice2
Let's say that returned 2.
假设这个返回值为 2
So dice1 has 4 in it,
所以 dice1 里的值是 4
and dice2 has 2 in it.
dice2 里的是 2
And then we initialize the count variable to 1,
然后把变量 count 初始化为 1
and then we go to our while condition.
进行 while 条件判断
It's checking if dice1 and dice2 are not the same.
判断 dice1 和 dice2 是否相同
In this case, 4 and 2 are not the same,
这里 4 和 2 并不相同
so our loop condition is true which means we step inside our loop,
所以循环条件为真 我们需要进入循环
and we re-roll our dice,
重掷骰子
calling rollDice twice again,
再次调用两次 rollDice 函数
and updating the dice values 1 and 2.
更新 dice1 和 2 的值
So let's say this time dice1 became 6,
假设这次 dice1 的值变为 6
and dice2 became 5,
dice2 的值变为 5
and then after that, we add 1 to our variable count,
之后给变量 count 加 1
updating it to become 2 instead of 1.
将其从 1 更新为 2
Where each the closing brackets of the while loop,
我们已经到了 while 循环的右括号
so we go back up and then we perform this comparison again.
所以回到这上面来 再次进行比较
Our dice1 and dice2 not the same.
我们的 dice1 和 dice2 不一样
Well, 6 and 5 are not the same, so that's true.
6 和 5 的确不一样 所以条件为真
So we step inside our loop again,
再次进入循环
and we update dice1 and dice2 using the rollDice again.
再次用 rollDice 更新 dice1 和 dice2
Let's say this time, we got 2 and 3.
假设这一次我们得到的值为 2 和 3
We add 1 to the count again,
count 再加 1
updating it to 3.
更新为 3
And then we go back up and perform our loop condition.
然后回到上面 继续进行循环条件判断
We check if dice1 and dice2 are not the same,
判断 dice1 和 dice2 是否相同
and 2 and 3 are not the same,
2 和 3 不相同
so that's true which means we step inside our loop again.
所以条件为真 我们得再进入循环
And then we update dice1 and dice2 again.
再次更新 dice1 和 dice2
Let's say this time we get 1 and 1,
假设这次我们得到了 1 和 1
and then we add 1 to our count making it 4
给 count 加 1 使其变为 4
which means that we've rolled our dice four times so far.
也就是说到目前为止我们共投掷了 4 次
And then we go back up and do our loop condition comparison.
然后再回来 进行循环条件判断
This time, dice1 and dice2 are the same.
这一次 dice1 和 dice2 一样了
So this check here evaluates to false which means our while loop is no
所以条件判断结果为假
longer going to step inside and just drop to
也就是说 while 循环不会再执行内部代码
the closed curly brackets here and continue the program.
直接跳到了这里的右花括号 程序继续往下执行
And since we only have this return count after the loop,
不过这里循环后只有返回 count 值的指令
so that means we return 4.
所以我们返回出值 4
Basically stating that we needed four rolls of those two dice until we got a match.
也就是说 等到两个骰子点数相同 我们已经投掷了四次
Now can you think of what we need to change in this code
你觉得我们要怎么修改这个代码
here to make it work for three dice instead of two?
才能让它适用于三个骰子的情景而非两个呢？